<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Pipeline Mechanisms on Heimdall</title><link>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/configuration/rules/pipeline_mechanisms/</link><description>Recent content in Pipeline Mechanisms on Heimdall</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 18:56:56 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dadrus.github.io/docs/configuration/rules/pipeline_mechanisms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Mechanisms Overview</title><link>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/configuration/rules/pipeline_mechanisms/overview/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 18:56:56 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/configuration/rules/pipeline_mechanisms/overview/</guid><description>All mechanisms supported by heimdall fall into following categories:
Authenticators, which inspect HTTP requests for presence of authentication objects, like e.g. the presence of a specific cookie. If such objects exist, authenticators verify the related authentication status and obtain information about the corresponding subject. A subject, could be a user who tries to use particular functionality of the upstream service, a machine (if you have machine-2-machine interaction), or something different.</description></item><item><title>Authenticators</title><link>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/configuration/rules/pipeline_mechanisms/authenticators/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 18:56:56 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/configuration/rules/pipeline_mechanisms/authenticators/</guid><description>Authenticators inspect HTTP requests for presence of authentication objects, like e.g. the presence of a specific cookie. If such objects exist, authenticators verify the related authentication status and obtain information about the corresponding subject. A subject, could be a user, trying to use particular functionality of the upstream service, a machine (if you have machine-2-machine interaction), or something different. Authenticators ensure the subject is authenticated and the information available about it is valid.</description></item><item><title>Authorizers</title><link>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/configuration/rules/pipeline_mechanisms/authorizers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 18:57:03 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/configuration/rules/pipeline_mechanisms/authorizers/</guid><description>Authorizers ensure that the Subject obtained via an authenticator has the required permissions to submit the given HTTP request and thus to execute the corresponding logic in the upstream service. E.g. a specific endpoint of the upstream service might only be accessible to a &amp;#34;user&amp;#34; from the &amp;#34;admin&amp;#34; group, or to an HTTP request if a specific HTTP header is set.
Authorizer Types The following sections describe the available authorizer types in more detail.</description></item><item><title>Contextualizers</title><link>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/configuration/rules/pipeline_mechanisms/contextualizers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 18:57:10 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/configuration/rules/pipeline_mechanisms/contextualizers/</guid><description>Contextualizers enrich the information about the Subject obtained via an authenticator mechanism with further information, required by either the endpoint of the upstream service itself or an authorizer mechanism. This can be handy if the actual authentication system doesn’t have all information about the subject (which is usually the case in microservice architectures), or if dynamic information about the subject, like the current location based on the IP address, is required.</description></item><item><title>Finalizers</title><link>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/configuration/rules/pipeline_mechanisms/finalizers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 18:57:16 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/configuration/rules/pipeline_mechanisms/finalizers/</guid><description>Finalizers, as the name implies, finalize the execution of the pipeline and enrich the request with data such as subject information or authentication tokens required by the upstream service. The available options range from adding a simple header over a structured JWT in a specific header, to driving specific protocols, e.g. to obtain a token required by the upstream service.
Finalizer Types The following sections describe the available finalizer types in more detail.</description></item><item><title>Error Handlers</title><link>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/configuration/rules/pipeline_mechanisms/error_handlers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 18:57:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/configuration/rules/pipeline_mechanisms/error_handlers/</guid><description>Error Handlers are responsible for execution of logic if any of the authenticators, authorizers, contextualizers or finalizers fails. The error handler mechanisms range from a simple error response to the client which sent the request to sophisticated ones, supporting complex logic and redirects.
Error Handler Types The following sections describe the available error handler types in more detail. Some of these may support or require additional configuration. The corresponding properties are annotated with mandatory, respectively optional to denote configuration requirement, as well as with overridable, not overriddable and partially overridable to indicate whether the property can be overridden in a rule pipeline.</description></item></channel></rss>