<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Observability on Heimdall</title><link>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/configuration/observability/</link><description>Recent content in Observability on Heimdall</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 22:11:50 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dadrus.github.io/docs/configuration/observability/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Metrics</title><link>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/configuration/observability/metrics/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 22:16:45 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/configuration/observability/metrics/</guid><description>As of today, heimdall only supports Prometheus as metrics backend, which is also enabled by default by exposing available metrics on 0.0.0.0:9000/metrics endpoint.
Configuration Metrics configuration can be adjusted in the prometheus property, which lives in the metrics property of heimdall&amp;rsquo;s configuration and supports following properties.
Host By making use of the host (string) property, you can specify the TCP/IP address on which heimdall should listen for connections from client applications.</description></item><item><title>Tracing</title><link>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/configuration/observability/tracing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 18:56:12 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/configuration/observability/tracing/</guid><description>Heimdall allows visualization of call flows in your infrastructure. It does this by using OpenTracing, an open standard designed for distributed tracing.
Following tracing backends are currently supported:
Jaeger Instana Configuration By default, tracing is disabled, but can be configured in the tracing property of heimdall&amp;rsquo;s configuration and supports following properties.
Service Name By setting the service_name (string) property, you can adjust the service name, appearing for Heimdall for your tracing backend.</description></item><item><title>Logging</title><link>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/configuration/observability/logging/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 18:56:07 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/configuration/observability/logging/</guid><description>Heimdall logs concern everything that happens to Heimdall itself (startup, configuration, events, shutdown, and so on). Logs are written to stdout by default in text format.
Configuration Logging configuration can be adjusted in the log property of heimdall&amp;rsquo;s configuration and supports following properties.
Format By default, logs are written in text format, which can also be changed by using the format (string) option. Following formats are supported:
text - The default one.</description></item></channel></rss>