<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Rules on Heimdall</title><link>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/rules/</link><description>Recent content in Rules on Heimdall</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 23:31:50 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dadrus.github.io/docs/rules/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Regular Rule</title><link>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/rules/regular_rule/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 22:13:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/rules/regular_rule/</guid><description>In simplest case a regular rule will just reuse mechanisms from a previously defined catalogue in its pipelines. In more complex cases a rule can reconfigure parts of used mechanisms. Which parts can be reconfigured, respectively overridden are mechanism specific and described in the mechanism specific documentation. Reconfiguration is always limited to the particular rule pipeline and does not affect other rules.
Configuration A single regular rule consists of the following properties:</description></item><item><title>Default Rule</title><link>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/rules/default_rule/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 22:13:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/rules/default_rule/</guid><description>Configuration The configuration of the default rule can be done by making use of the default_rule property and configuring the options shown below.
The default rule does not support all the properties, which can be configured in an regular rule. E.g. it can not be used to forward requests to an upstream service, heimdall is protecting. So, if you operate heimdall in the reverse proxy mode, the default rule should be configured to reject requests.</description></item><item><title>Rule Sets</title><link>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/rules/rule_sets/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 22:13:32 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/rules/rule_sets/</guid><description>Depending on the configured provider, the rules can be then loaded from e.g. a plain old configuration file, residing in the local file system, or even from a Kubernetes environment as a custom resource. Thus, the structure and format of a rule set depends on the provider used to load it. As of today, there are two supported formats:
as a regular JSON/YAML file, the so-called regular rule set, and</description></item><item><title>Rule Providers</title><link>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/rules/providers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 22:13:54 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/rules/providers/</guid><description>Providers allow definition of sources to load the rule sets from. These make heimdall’s behavior dynamic. All providers, you want to enable for a heimdall instance must be configured within the providers section of heimdall’s configuration.
Below, you can find the description and configuration options for currently supported providers.
Filesystem The filesystem provider allows loading of regular rule sets in JSON or YAML format from a file system.
Configuration The configuration of this provider goes into the file_system property.</description></item></channel></rss>