<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Services on Heimdall</title><link>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/services/</link><description>Recent content in Services on Heimdall</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 23:11:50 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dadrus.github.io/docs/services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Decision Service</title><link>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/services/decision/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 18:55:36 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/services/decision/</guid><description>To make use of this service you have to start heimdall with heimdall serve decision or heimdall serve decision --envoy-grpc. By default, heimdall listens on 0.0.0.0:4456 endpoint for incoming requests in this mode of operation and also configures useful default timeouts, as well as buffer limits. No other options are configured. You can, and should however adjust the configuration for your needs.
Configuration The configuration of the Decision service can be adjusted in the decision property, which lives in the serve property of heimdall’s configuration and supports the following properties.</description></item><item><title>Proxy Service</title><link>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/services/proxy/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 18:55:45 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/services/proxy/</guid><description>To make use of this service you have to start Heimdall with heimdall serve proxy. By default, Heimdall listens on 0.0.0.0:4455 endpoint for incoming requests in this mode of operation and also configures useful default timeouts, amount of possible upstream connections is active and idle state, as well as buffer limits. No other options are configured. You can, and should however adjust the configuration for your needs.
Configuration The configuration of the Proxy endpoint can be adjusted in the proxy property, which lives in the serve property of heimdall’s configuration and supports the following properties.</description></item><item><title>Management Service</title><link>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/services/management/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 18:55:36 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/services/management/</guid><description>By default, Heimdall listens on 0.0.0.0:4457 endpoint for incoming requests and also configures useful default timeouts as well as buffer limits. No other options are configured. You can however adjust the configuration for your needs.
This service exposes the health and the JWKS endpoints.
Configuration The configuration for of the Management endpoint can be adjusted in the management property, which lives in the serve property of heimdall’s configuration and supports the following properties.</description></item></channel></rss>