<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mechanisms on Heimdall</title><link>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/mechanisms/</link><description>Recent content in Mechanisms on Heimdall</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2023 23:14:56 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dadrus.github.io/docs/mechanisms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Catalogue</title><link>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/mechanisms/catalogue/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 15:01:21 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/mechanisms/catalogue/</guid><description>As described in Concepts section, mechanisms must be defined and configured before these can be used in rules. That is happening in the so-called mechanisms catalogue. On start up heimdall instantiates all defined and configured mechanisms and makes these available for usage in rules.
Catalogue Configuration The corresponding mechanisms catalogue resides under the mechanisms property of heimdall static configuration and is organized based on mechanism categories as also shown in the snippet below.</description></item><item><title>Objects, Templating &amp; Co</title><link>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/mechanisms/evaluation_objects/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Jan 2024 15:53:47 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/mechanisms/evaluation_objects/</guid><description>E.g. in one case, you want to have access to a particular request header. In another case you would like to add specific data to the resulting JWT created by heimdall. And in yet another case, you may want to check whether some expectations apply. These capabilities are described on this page.
Objects Objects represent state in the execution of a particular rule. These are the entities, either created or used by particular mechanisms and can represent things, like the actual request, the authenticated subject of the request and many more.</description></item><item><title>Authenticators</title><link>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/mechanisms/authenticators/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 18:56:56 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/mechanisms/authenticators/</guid><description>Some of the supported authenticator types may support or require additional configuration. The corresponding properties are annotated with mandatory, respectively optional to denote configuration requirement, as well as with overridable, not overriddable and partially overridable to indicate whether the property can be overridden in a rule pipeline.
Unauthorized This authenticator rejects all requests as unauthenticated (on HTTP response code level this is then mapped to 401 Unauthorized, hence the type name).</description></item><item><title>Authorizers</title><link>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/mechanisms/authorizers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 18:57:03 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/mechanisms/authorizers/</guid><description>Some of the authorizers may support or require additional configuration. The corresponding properties are annotated with mandatory, respectively optional to denote configuration requirement, as well as with overridable, not overriddable and partially overridable to indicate whether the property can be overridden in a rule pipeline.
Allow As the name implies, this authorizer allows any request passing through. This authorizer type also doesn’t have any configuration options.
To enable the usage of this authorizer, you have to set the type property to allow.</description></item><item><title>Contextualizers</title><link>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/mechanisms/contextualizers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 18:57:10 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/mechanisms/contextualizers/</guid><description>Some of the contextualizers may support or require additional configuration. The corresponding properties are annotated with mandatory, respectively optional to denote configuration requirement, as well as with overridable, not overriddable and partially overridable to indicate whether the property can be overridden in a rule pipeline.
Generic This mechanism allows you to communicate to any API you want to fetch further information about the subject. Typical scenario is getting specific attributes for later authorization purposes which are not known to the authentication system and thus were not made available in Subject’s Attributes property.</description></item><item><title>Finalizers</title><link>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/mechanisms/finalizers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 18:57:16 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/mechanisms/finalizers/</guid><description>Some finalizers may support or require additional configuration. The corresponding properties are annotated with mandatory, respectively optional to denote configuration requirement, as well as with overridable, not overriddable and partially overridable to indicate whether the property can be overridden in a rule pipeline.
Noop As the name implies, this finalizer does nothing. This finalizer type also doesn’t have any configuration options.
To enable the usage of this finalizer, you have to set the type property to noop.</description></item><item><title>Error Handlers</title><link>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/mechanisms/error_handlers/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 18:57:29 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://dadrus.github.io/docs/mechanisms/error_handlers/</guid><description>Some of the error handlers may support or require additional configuration. The corresponding properties are annotated with mandatory, respectively optional to denote configuration requirement, as well as with overridable, not overriddable and partially overridable to indicate whether the property can be overridden in a rule pipeline.
Default This mechanism is always there and is executed if no other error handler mechanism is responsible for the error. Actually, there is no need to explicitly configure it.</description></item></channel></rss>